# SAMUEL OYEKEYE

Tallinn, Estonia 10111 | +37257409011 | samoyekeye@gmail.com | WWW: https://samoyekeye.com

# Summary

Software engineer with strong problem-solving, software development, and system design skills. Well-versed in current technology and writing code to create software systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Extensive experience in creating mobile and web applications using Industry- standard development and deployment practices. Strategic thinker with a strong drive and passion for developing optimal software solutions that suit user specs.

### **Skills**

- Agile Development Methodologies
- Product Development
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Interface Design and Implementation
- Affinity for JS Frameworks (ReactJS, AngularJS, VueJS, Express JS...)
- User Experience Design
- Code Review

# **Experience**

#### **Software Tainer**

**Software Development Academy** — Remote

Mar 2020 to Current

Contract trainer at SDA, an online software training academy, where I teach
Javascript, HTML and CSS, Java as well as core concepts of programming and software
development, also training students in workshops sponsored by companies like
Accenture.

### **Senior Frontend Developer**

Jan 2023 to Dec 2023

**Qminder** — London, United Kingdom

- Developed user interface components and implemented them with angular 16 following well-known Angular workflows.
- Built reusable UI components and front-end libraries for consumer use.
- Maintained and improved Qminder software and website with feature improvements and UI migrations.

#### Senior Frontend Developer

Jan 2022 to Nov 2022

Adcash OÜ — Tallinn, Estonia

- Developed and maintained Adcash software as resident senior frontend developer.
- Migrated software written in Vue JS from Vue2 to Vue3.
- Organized small workshops on Vue framework changes to help level up code quality as a team.

#### Lead Frontend Engineer (Remote)

Apr 2018 to Dec 2021

Safaricom PLC — Nairobi, Kenya

- Led a remote team of 9 frontend developers to build and deploy Safaricom's first self-service portal using Next JS.
- Set up CI/CD pipeline for 2 separate user-facing dashboards.
- Handled planning, allocating and reviewing tasks within the frontend team.

# **Education and Training**

## Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Nov 2019

University of Lagos - Lagos, Nigeria

# **Technology**

React JS Angular JS

Express JS

React Native

Vue JS

Springboot (Intermediary)